as we said before we have to figure out
the dependencies even though this
program has output an anti dependences
again for LT all we care about is the
true dependencies so we could rename
this programming J get just the true
dependencies or we could just look at
where the true dependencies are here so
we have here this is using r1 this is
using our 2 and r1 but it doesn't matter
because this is going to be a longer r7
and r8 are not depending on anything yet
r3 and r 7 there is a dependence here R
1 and R 1 we are dependent on this
instruction here for both of them really
and then R 7 and r 7 we are not using
any of them again we are overwriting R 1
here we are overwriting R 1 here and so
on but that doesn't matter because after
renaming all of that would be gone so
now it's time to figure out what can
execute in which cycle in the first
cycle we can execute this one we cannot
execute this one because it depends on
that we cannot execute this one because
it has to wait for the second
instruction we can execute this one it
doesn't depend on anything we can not
execute this one yet because it has a
dependence this one also but this one
can execute so in the first cycle we
managed to do our three instructions now
this instruction only depends on
instruction that is done after cycle one
so this can be done in second cycle this
one actually depends on instruction that
is done in second cycle so it will have
to wait until the third cycle this one
depends on an instruction that is done
in the third cycle so this is going to
be executed in the fourth cycle this one
can actually execute in the second cycle
it depends on the instruction that
executes in the first cycle and that's
it so it can be done in the second cycle
so what we have is the last instruction
that finishes in cycle four and we
managed to execute seven instructions
over that time so we have seven over
four which if you want to calculate it
out it's gonna end up being 1.75